Hello everyone, how are you all? I am
Amit Raj Sharma, your personal advisor, and you are
watching Yudh Real. At the very beginning of the video, I
want to tell you that there are two options available in the Akshay Plan of Aditya
Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited. The
first is the Long Term Income Option and the second is the
Life Income Option. We have already shared the details of the Long Term Income Option
with you on our channel. The
thumbnail of the video is at the top of your screen.
If you watch this video,
you will also be able to know the Guaranteed Surrender Value of the Long Term Income Option, the
Maturity Benefit, the
Death Benefit, and the Income Benefit. To
know more about it, you will have to go to the Life Insurance
Playlist, and the link to the Life Insurance
Playlist is given in the description of the video. So, let's
start today's video
and learn the details of the Whole Life Income Option of the Akshay Plan of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Company Limited.
First, we will talk about the eligibility
criteria. In the Whole Life Income Option, we
get two choices of cover. The first is that
we remain covered till we reach the age of 85 years. The
second is that we remain covered till the plan is in place.  That
till we turn 100 years old, we should remain in our policy. The
policy limit is for ages six to 55
years and for minors, we take a plan till they become adults, there are
no benefit tables till they become adults. The premium payment
term option is also the same. Here the
policy term is from six years to 15 years.
If you want cover till 85 years onwards, then you will
subtract your age from 85. If you
want cover till 100 years, then you will subtract your age from 100. It will come out
positive
for you. The minimum premium
limit is Rs 24000 per annum. The minimum
assault limit is Rs
1245060. With this option also
you get all the modes of premium, if you
take it annually, half-yearly, quarterly, monthly, then auto debit will be done
from your account and it is possible that
you may have to pay more than one premium and one
thing to be noted is that the maximum
submergence limit, which is the
limit of maximum premium, depends
as per the rules.  The board
will approve how much right you have and it is
called no limit.
To understand the simple benefit, we will take an example of this option. Let us take a
gentleman who is 40 years old and
wants the option of life cover. For this reason,
he took the Whole Life Income Option of Akshay Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited
and he
wants to pay an annual premium of ₹1 lakh.
Accordingly, he
took a premium payment term of 10 years. So, in 10 years, the total
premium paid here will be 10
lakhs because he has
taken an annual premium of ₹1 lakh here. Along with
this, the annual premium of ₹1 lakh has been
considered here. This will come in band number
three.
In the previous video, you have been told about the band,
why it should come in band number three because the premium is ₹1
lakh and if it is more than ₹1 lakh i.e.
₹1999, then the band comes for free.
According to that, you can use all the matches and factors like the pain
benefit factor also.  Yes, it is of 1080
percent, on which it is applicable on annual
premium, then 1 lakh less 1000 will come out 80%,
so we have reached an agreement of ₹10 lakh ₹80000,
now we have to withdraw the
policy term, so we will subtract the
age of the gentleman from 100, by withdrawing here
because we are taking online cover, hence
we have considered cover up to 100 years here,
now they want that whatever bonus is there, they should get that
cash bonus and keep getting it annually,
we are manipulating the rate of bonus here, we are adjusting it like that, the
basic understanding is 4 percent of the road,
they will keep getting bonus every year, that is
₹40 on a SAM Assort of ₹1000,
so the first installment will be
4 percent of 10 lakh 80 thousand, then it will be ₹43200,
now as long as they remain in the policy,
they can get this amount every year
because the bonus is
not confirmed, right maturity
benefit  What will happen as per our example, if there is any
cashback plus last
installment of cash bonus plus terminal
bonus, then our total amount will be Rs 10 lakh 80 thousand, the
last
installment of Rs 43200 will be the cashback and terminal
bonus, if the company has announced it, then
its calculation will also be done and given,
so the maturity benefit will be Rs 1123200
plus terminal bonus, now we know
about the benefit here, so let's take an example, you will get this much,
right, we can assume
minimum understanding and what is death, understanding
means basic understanding and we will compare
11 times the annual premium, then
our amount will be Rs 11 lakh here
and the total paid premium, that is, the base
premium on the total paid, in which tax is
not included, we will calculate 105% of it, if
we assume that after paying premium for 10 years,
if there is death, then it will become 105%,
1050000, we will compare everything  So if the
amount of 11 lakhs is more then everything will be added up to
11 lakhs. Now let us assume that
when Mr. Jai died, he
crossed the age of 65 years. In such a situation,
how many years did he live while being in the policy? He
lived for 25 years. In 25 years, if he had been getting annual bonus at the
rate of 4% of the basic time sum assured, then
what would be the total amount he would have received? If we
multiply 43200 by 25, then
he would have got ₹10 lakh ₹80000. Okay, so
I can assume that before his death, he has already
received ₹10 lakh ₹10000. So
what will be the grand benefit here? Our 11 lakh rupees plus
terminal bonus will be paid to his nominee here.
Okay, and the policy will be
closed here. Along with this, the
last installment of cash bonus can
also be received, that is, 43200 can also be received.
If the bonus keeps getting announced like this, then
now we assume that here  Mr.
Jain has been paying premiums continuously for 6 years and
after that he is not willing to pay future premiums
and he also does not want to surrender. The reason is that he does
not want to do so because
he has seen the previous part and he
knows that there will be a loss on surrendering. So
in such a situation, the policy will be converted into a
reduced period policy after the grace period
and the reduced speed up
factor will be calculated here. He has paid
premium for six years. The premium payment term
was of 10 years, so six was divided by 10,
so zero point six. Here the reduced
speed up factor comes out which we have
written as RPU factor. So
what will be the benefit on the maturity? What will be the paid up maturity
benefit? It will be
multiplied by that and if we multiply PU factor by
100000 by 19.5, then his
maturity benefit here becomes Rs. 648000.
What is the paid up maturity which is
more than the total paid premium,
but we take it because it is
also logical that till the age of 100, everyone  If he does
not survive, what will happen if he dies in the middle of the policy? If the
sum assured on death is
multiplied by the RPF factor, then
in such a case, there will be a paid-up benefit of ₹68000 which will be
paid to his nominee. This
amount will also be more than the total paid premium.
But in such a case, the cash
bonus that was paid will now be given but only once
because
if he did not already receive the bonus in the year in which he paid the premium, then
after that the policy is getting
converted into a reduced paid-up policy, then he will
get the bonus of that year
in the form of installments, in such a case the amount will be ₹25920.
Otherwise, when the policy gets
converted into a reduced paid-up policy, there is
no bonus table of any kind, be it
terminal bonus, your interview
bonus, or cash bonus. But if
instead of taking the cash bonus, you have
accumulated the bonus, that is, you have collected it
through out the policy, as is the case
in an endowment plan, then the accumulated
bonus will be given to him on
maturity as well as on the maturity date.  There is
maturity benefit as well as pain benefit. If we
talk about the free loan period, if you
buy directly, the plan is for 15 days and if you buy
indirectly, it is for 30 days.
Now after watching both the videos, if you
check the PDF on the Telegram channel,
you will understand everything.
Thank you very much for watching the video till the end.
Understand one thing yourself and make others understand too that
insurance is a protection. Protection is
never taken incompletely and please make it a
habit to read the policy document.
[Music]